# Nicolás Urdaneta

Phone: (+57) 3212455640

n.urdaneta@uniandes.edu.co

#### Profile

I am a research assistant at the Economics Faculty at Universidad de Los Andes, Colombia, working for Marcela Eslava on firm dynamics, productivity, and market power. I hold a M.A and a B.A. in economics from Universidad de Los Andes. I am primarily interested in approaching problems through empirical work with structural models. My current interests in research are towards firm dynamics, innovation, trade, economic development, and applied econometrics. I have also worked on other topics in independent projects that include internal migration and displacement in Colombia and gender bias in student evaluations of teaching.

#### **EDUCATION**

2019 - 2021	M.A. Economics, cum laude, Universidad de los Andes - Bogotá, Colombia
2015 - 2019	B.A. Economics, <i>cum laude</i> , Universidad de los Andes - Bogotá, Colombia

#### Research Experience

Jun. 2019 -	Research Assistant for Marcela Eslava, Full-Professor and Economics Faculty
Present	Dean, Universidad de Los Andes. Main research projects joint with John Haltiwanger and Marcela Meléndez.
Dec. 2019 - Feb. 2020	Data research assistant for Adriana Corredor-Waldron, Postdoctoral Research Associate, Princeton University.

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

GRADUATE TEACHER A	Assistant - U	NIVERSIDAD	DE Los	Andes
--------------------	---------------	------------	--------	-------

2020 II Impact Evaluation for Public Policy (prof. Adriana Camacho)

2020 Summer Intermediate Econometrics (prof. Mateo Arbeláez)

2020 I World Economic History (prof. Leopoldo Fergusson and Juan Sebastián Galán) 2019 II-2020 I Intermediate Macroeconomics (prof. David Pérez and Andrés Zambrano)

## Undergraduate Teacher Assistant - Universidad de Los Andes

2018 II - 2019 I Monetary Policy and Theory
2018 Summer Intermediate Econometrics
2017 Summer Intermediate Microeconomics

2017 II Mathematical Methods for Economics

2017 I Pentagon. Study hall for Calculus 3, integral Calculus, Linear Algebra, and

Differential Calculus.

2016 II Integral Calculus

#### Working Papers

Market concentration, market fragmentation, and inequality in Latin America. (2021). UNDP LAC Working Paper No. 11. Background Paper for the UNDP LAC Regional Human Development Report 2021. With *Marcela Eslava and Marcela Meléndez*. Document available here.

"Talented" Men and "Kind" Women? Gender Bias in Student Evaluations of Teaching. (2021). Documento CEDE No. 46. (Master's thesis). Document available here. In the media: El Espectador.

# Work in progress

Equilibrium Gender Discrimination in Student Evaluation of Teaching. With Sara Ayllon, Lars Lefgren, Richard Patterson, and Olga Stoddard.

Reconciling the Effects of Migration: Do the Opportunity Costs Shape the Local Effects?. With Mateo Arbeláez and Juan Sebastián Muñoz.

## AWARDS

2011	Sixth place National Colombian Mathematical Olympics 30th Edition. First
	level category.
2019	One of the best results in the Colombian higher education examinations
	(Saber-Pro). The award was given to 1,324 graduates out of over 240,000.
2019	Placed in the top 3% of the previous 5 years of graduates in the B.A. in
	economics, Los Andes University (cum laude).
2021	Placed in the top 3% of the previous 5 years of graduates in the M.A. in
	economics, Los Andes University (cum laude).

#### OTHER EXPERIENCE

Supuestos Economics Magazine (2016 - 2019). This is the economics student's magazine from Universidad de Los Andes. I held multiple roles: Editorial Director (2019), Revision and Edition Sub Director (2018), Communications Sub Director (2017 II). Six publications in printed edition, including two main articles. Link to website (in Spanish).

# SKILLS

Stata, R & Latex	Advanced	Python & Julia	Basic
Languages			
English	Fluent	Spanish	Native Language
REFERENCES			
Marcela Eslava	Full Professor and Econom meslava@uniandes.edu.co	ics Faculty Dean, Un	iversidad de Los Andes.
John Haltiwanger	Distinguished University Pro	ofessor, University of M	Maryland. halt@umd.edu
Adriana Camacho	Associate Professor, Univers	idad de Los Andes. ad	lcamach@uniandes.edu.co
Lars Lefgren	Department Chair and lars_lefgren@byu.edu	Professor, Bringha	am Young University.